iperceptions.com 2016-03-05

# Privacy Policy | iPerceptions

**Last updated: December 10, 2015**

PREAMBLE

PLEASE READ THIS PRIVACY POLICY CAREFULLY. CAPITALIZED WORDS OR EXPRESSIONS SHALL HAVE THE MEANING ASCRIBED TO THEM IN THIS PRIVACY POLICY. IPERCEPTIONS® (“We”, “Us” or “Our”) IS COMMITTED TO PROTECTING THE PRIVACY AND SECURITY OF ITS USERS BY MAINTAINING THE HIGHEST STANDARDS OF CONFIDENTIALITY AND SECURITY FOR ALL DATA COLLECTED FROM RESPONDENTS AS WELL AS SITE VISITORS, SUBSCRIBERS AND OTHERS USERS (“USERS”). BY USING, VISITING OR OTHERWISE ACCESSING THE WEBSITE OR THE SERVICES IN ANY WAY (INCLUDING BY RESPONDING TO SURVEYS OR OTHER COMMUNICATIONS RECEIVED FROM OTHER USERS OF THE WEBSITE AND/OR THE SERVICES, BY VIEWING, DOWNLOADING OR UPLOADING ANY CONTENT OR MATERIAL MADE AVAILABLE VIA THE WEBSITE OR THE SERVICES OR BY BROWSING), YOU EXPRESSLY CONSENT TO THE COLLECTION, USE, DISCLOSURE AND PROCESSING OF INFORMATION, INCLUDING YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION IN ACCORDANCE WITH THE TERMS OF THIS PRIVACY POLICY THAT YOU HEREBY ACKNOWLEDGE TO HAVE READ AND ACCEPTED. YOU MAY OPT OUT AT ANY TIME IN THE MANNER DESCRIBED IN THIS PRIVACY POLICY, OR CHOOSE NOT TO PROVIDE AN ANSWER TO ANY GIVEN SURVEY QUESTION, IF ANY.  

iPerceptions has been awarded TRUSTe’s Privacy Seal signifying that this Privacy Policy and practices have been reviewed by TRUSTe for compliance with [TRUSTe’s program requirements](http://www.truste.com/privacy-program-requirements/) and the [TRUSTed Cloud Program Requirements](http://www.truste.com/privacy-program-requirements/TRUSTed-cloud/) including transparency, accountability and choice regarding the collection and use of Your personal information.

iPerceptions complies with the U.S.-EU Safe Harbor Framework and the U.S.-Swiss Safe Harbor Framework as administered by the United States Department of Commerce with respect to such Information that it receives about individuals located in the EU and Switzerland. iPerceptions has certified that it adheres to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, and enforcement. To learn more about the Safe Harbor program, and to view our certification, please visit <http://www.export.gov/safeharbor>.

To contact iPerceptions regarding this privacy policy or the Safe Harbor program, you may reach iPerceptions using the contact information provided at the bottom of this policy.

This Privacy Policy and the TRUSTe Program covers the collection, use and disclosure of information iPerceptions collects through its websites www.iperceptions.com and through survey responses collected through iPerceptions’ platform on behalf of Customers who use Services. The use of information collected through the Services shall be limited to the purpose of providing the Services for which the Customer has engaged iPerceptions, and other purposes as provided in this Privacy Policy, the Terms of Use or any other agreement between iPerceptions and You.

In order to view our relationship with TRUSTe please visit the validation page visible by clicking on the TRUSTe seal. If you have questions or complaints regarding this Privacy Policy or practices, please contact us (See Contact Us Section). If you are not satisfied with our response You can contact TRUSTe.

1. DEFINITIONS  
Whenever used in this Privacy Policy, the following terms have the meaning ascribed to them below and all other terms not defined in this Section 1 shall have the meaning ascribed to them in this Privacy Policy:  
“Cookies” are software methods and protocols used for storing data in a web browser. For the purpose of this document, Cookies refers to both HTTP Cookies as defined by the IETF and the local and session storage methods of the Web Storage specification as defined by the World Wide Web consortium. “Customer” means iPerceptions’ customer to who iPerceptions licenses the Services.

“iPerceptions” means iPerceptions, Inc., located at 3575 Boulevard St-Laurent Suite 310 Montreal, Québec H2X 2T7 Canada or any other successor location.

“Privacy Policy” shall mean this privacy policy which may be changed in accordance with its terms, as updated from time to time.

“Respondents” means survey respondents or other participants who interact with the Services as a result of such respondents’ or participants’ relationship with a Customer.

“Services” means any products and services provided to Customers by iPerceptions or by any of its agent, reseller or partner.

“Terms of Use” means the current online Terms of Use issued by iPerceptions which may be changed in accordance with its terms, a copy of which can be found at the URL location provided below (or any successor URL thereof) or any other location iPerceptions may make available to You, which is incorporated herein by reference and which You, on Your behalf and on behalf of the other Users, if any, hereby acknowledge having read and accepted in its entirety:  

“Website” means iPerceptions.com and any other website made available to You and Your Users and operated by iPerceptions or by its authorized third party hosting entity acting on behalf of iPerceptions, and any and all sub-domains thereof.

2. PRIVACY POLICIES OF THIRD PARTIES  
Third party payment provider's and privacy statement of third parties (including, the Customers’), including security practices, may apply to Your information or when You respond to a survey. iPerceptions encourages You to read those privacy statements before providing Your information.

3. INFORMATION COLLECTION & USE

3.1. Information Provided by You as User  
You may be asked on any Website how You heard about iPerceptions, to provide contact information in exchange for access to white papers or other downloadable content on our Website. iPerceptions may use this information for sales and marketing purposes, to respond to Your inquiry, or correspond with You if necessary. We may also collect name, email addresses, mailing address, and phone number, age, gender and credit card information.

3.2. Information Provided by Respondents  
If You are a Respondent, iPerceptions may collect and store information from You on behalf of the Customer whose survey You have responded to. The survey responses are owned and managed by the Customer. The Customer is responsible for the survey data. If You have any question, You may contact the Customer directly as iPerceptions is not responsible for the content of the survey You have responded to or Your responses to it. Customers may have their own privacy policies that detail how said Customers handle Your personal information or other information. iPerceptions encourages You to read carefully any such policy and learn about the privacy practices of those third parties. As between You and iPerceptions, Your submission of personal information is voluntary and optional. You may opt out of responding at any time. However, if You do respond, You consent to its provision to iPerceptions for the purpose of delivering the Services to our Customer.

3.3. Automatically Collected Information  
iPerceptions gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, the IP addresses of Respondents, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), mobile carrier, mobile device, operating system, referring/exit pages, the URLs of sites from which an User arrives or leaves a website, date/time stamp, and clickstream data. iPerceptions uses this information to analyze trends, to monitor the effectiveness of marketing efforts, including which websites refer the most people to iPerceptions, to deliver iPerceptions or third party advertising to Users, to administer the Website, to understand users’ movements around the Website, and to improve the quality of the Services and Website performance, to aid solving technical problems, and to gather demographic information about iPerceptions’ User base as a whole (The IP addresses are analyzed in the aggregate). We do not link this automatically collected data to other information we collect about You, except where You have chosen to provide it. iPerceptions uses Cookies and other technologies to help personalize and improve the User’s online experience and the overall quality of the Services. Cookies cannot be used to run programs or deliver viruses to Your computer or device. Cookies are uniquely assigned to You and can only be read by a web server in the domain that issued the cookie to You. iPerceptions may use a third-party tracking service that uses images, scripts, page tags (also known as web beacons) and other tracking technologies to track non-personal information about visitors to our Website in the aggregate. This data includes user statistics. iPerceptions will not request, access or otherwise track any location based information from Your mobile device. In the course of serving advertisements or optimizing the Services to Users, iPerceptions may allow authorized third parties to place or recognize a unique cookie on Your browser for the enhancement of Your User experience by providing more relevant advertising.

3.4. Information From Third Parties  
iPerceptions may collect Your personal information from third parties when You authorize those third parties to share Your information with iPerceptions.

3.5. Information Related to Data Collected for our Customers  
iPerceptions collects information under the direction of its Customers, and has no direct relationship with the individuals whose personal data it processes. If you are a customer of one of our Customers and would no longer like to be contacted by one of our Customers that use the Services, please contact the Customer that You interact with directly. Because iPerceptions is acting as the Customer’s agent, if You choose to opt-out of future emails, the opt-out will be Customer-specific, and does not apply to other emails sent by iPerceptions. Information collected in response to an email is handled in the same manner as other website visitor data, as described in this Privacy Statement. iPerceptions may transfer personal information to companies that help iPerceptions provide the Services. Transfers to subsequent third parties are covered by this Privacy Policy and the service agreements with our Customers. In certain instances, iPerceptions’ surveys include sweepstakes incentives. When a survey includes a sweepstakes incentive, entry in the sweepstakes is entirely optional. Survey responses may be submitted without entering the sweepstakes. Please refer to the specific sweepstakes rules for further detail. In all cases, any contact information collected by iPerceptions, including but not limited to name, email address, mailing address, and telephone number, is only used to manage the sweepstakes, subject to the sweepstakes rules and the terms of the Customer’s privacy policy.

3.6. Other General Uses  
We may provide your personal information to companies that provide services to help us with our business activities. These companies are authorized to use your personal information only as necessary to provide these services to us.

iPerceptions may use Your information to provide Services to Customers, to establish or maintain business relationships or provide them feedback. iPerceptions compiles data collected from its online surveys to produce benchmark reports for Customers as well as media and other interested parties. The information provided by Respondents on Customers’ online surveys is compiled and aggregated to create generic profiles of users of the websites being studied. Open-ended responses are compiled and reported as is. iPerceptions’ study process does not require iPerceptions to know nor to report the identity of any individual Respondent personally. Customers have the ability to export, share, or publish data from their surveys. iPerceptions provide various features to export, share, or publish Your survey questions, responses, and results in summary or detailed format. iPerceptions may also use Customer information, including online survey questions and Respondents’ responses, as well as aggregated data iPerceptions collects through survey results and transactional and performance data related to use of the Services to help analysis and to help iPerceptions provide and improve the Services.

3.7. Cookies and other Tracking Technologies  
iPerceptions and our partners (e.g. marketing partners, third party service providers, technology service providers), affiliates, or analytics or service providers, use technologies such as cookies, beacons, tags, and scripts, to analyze trends, administer the website, tracking users’ movements around the website, and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies by these companies on an individual and aggregated basis.

We use cookies for internal purposes to help us to provide You with a better user experience. The cookies help us understand how a website is used by visitors. From this information we can improve the way the site works and presents content to You. Users can control the use of cookies at the individual browser level. If you reject cookies, you may still use our services, but your ability to use some features or areas of our services may be limited.

We use Local Shared Objects, such as Flash cookies, and Local Storage, such as HTML5, to store content information and preferences. Third parties with whom we partner to provide certain features on our website or to display advertising based upon your web browsing activity also use HTML5 to collect and store information. Various browsers may offer their own management tools for removing HTML5. To manage Flash cookies, please click here:

http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager07.html

We partner with a third party to either display advertising on our Web site or to manage our advertising on other sites. Our third party partner may use technologies such as cookies to gather information about your activities on this site and other sites in order to provide you advertising based upon your browsing activities and interests. If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you interest-based ads, you may opt-out by clicking here (or if located in the European Union click here). Please note this does not opt you out of being served ads. You will continue to receive generic ads.

4. INFORMATION DISCLOSURE  
iPerceptions may transfer your personal information to third parties only in the ways that is described in this privacy policy, except in the following limited circumstances:  
1) information You expressly consent to be shared;  
2) when relating to anonymized information (individuals cannot be identified by it);  
3) when You decide to make the information indexable by search engines, to share or to distribute the information to people or otherwise to make it available to the public;  
4) to share the information iPerceptions collects on Customers' behalf with the Customer iPerceptions has collected the information on behalf of;  
5) to satisfy any applicable law, regulation, legal process or enforceable governmental request within or outside Your country of residence when iPerceptions has a good faith belief that the law requires it;  
6) to enforce this Privacy Policy, the Terms of Use, or a service agreement, including investigation of potential violations thereof;  
7) to detect, prevent, or otherwise address fraud, security or technical issues, or protect the operations or Users;  
8) to protect the rights, property or safety of iPerceptions, the Users, the public, or others;  
9) in connection with an acquisition, merger, change in control, debt financing, reorganization, sale of assets, bankruptcy or other change of iPerceptions’ corporate structure or status; or  
10) sweepstakes administrators, as necessary in connection with the performance of requested services or solutions, or as otherwise appropriate in connection with a legitimate need.

5. ACCESSING, CHANGING OR DELETING YOUR INFORMATION  
You need to contact the Customer if You want to access, update, or delete Your survey responses. iPerceptions cannot provide You with this access since survey responses are the Customer's information. In other situations, iPerceptions will endeavor to fulfill requests to correct, update or delete Your information unless such information is required to be retained by law, for legitimate business, technical or security purposes (such as storage in backup media created as part of our routine system backup procedures, or if jeopardizing the privacy of others) or, as provided in this Privacy Policy. iPerceptions will retain personal data it processes on behalf of its Customers for as long as needed to provide Services to Customers. iPerceptions will retain this personal information as necessary to comply with its legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce its agreements. If requested to remove data we will respond within a reasonable timeframe.

6. CHILDREN  
iPerceptions’ surveys and Website are not designed or intended for use by children under 13 and iPerceptions does not intentionally or knowingly collect data from children under 13 or allow them to register, although the sites we survey may offer children’s services for purchase by adults. If You are under 18, You should not participate in surveys or use any Website unless a parent or guardian is present. Children under 13 may not submit any information to iPerceptions, and if iPerceptions discovers that it has inadvertently gathered any such information for a child under 13 or such child has created an account, iPerceptions will take steps to delete any such information and close that account as soon as possible. Children over 13 should only provide iPerceptions with information if they have explicit permission from a parent or legal guardian. If Your child has submitted information, and You wish to review, change and/or delete such information as well as refuse to allow any further collection or use of the child’s information, or if You have reason to believe that this has occurred involving a child under 13, please contact iPerceptions (See Contact Us Section).

7. BLOGS, FORUMS, TESTIMONIALS, SOCIAL MEDIA WIDGETS  
1) If any Website offers publicly accessible blogs or community forums, You should be aware that any information You provide in these areas may be read, collected, and used by others who access them. To request removal of Your information from our blog or community forum, contact iPerceptions (See Contact Us section).  
2) ) iPerceptions post testimonials on the Website that You may submit to iPerceptions from time to time. iPerceptions always request permission to post Your testimonial on the Website, and iPerceptions may use Your information to contact You for the purpose of requesting such permission. 3) The Website and some surveys include social media features, such as the Facebook Like button and Widgets, such as the Share this button or interactive mini-programs that run on our site. These features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

8. EU SAFE HARBOR FRAMEWORK  
iPerceptions participates in the EU Safe Harbor Privacy Framework as administered by the United States Department of Commerce. To learn more about the Safe Harbor program, and to view our certification, please visit <http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/>.

9. SECURITY STATEMENT  
1) iPerceptions takes the security of the data collected very seriously however the Internet, not being a secured environment or any system being completely foolproof, iPerceptions does not warrant that information may not be accessed, copied, disclosed, altered, or destroyed by breach of any of our physical, technical, or managerial safeguards despite the security protections iPerceptions undertakes. iPerceptions uses secure server hosting locations with 24×7 security and monitoring, firewall protection, controlled access and encryption technology to protect Your data. The secrecy of Your password is Your responsibility.  
2) iPerceptions offers the use of a secure server. All supplied sensitive/credit information is transmitted via Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology and then encrypted into our PCI Compliant Payment gateway providers database only to be accessible by those authorized with special access rights to such systems, and are required to keep the information confidential. After a transaction, information such as credit cards numbers is not stored on our servers.  
3) iPerceptions takes reasonable security measures to protect against loss and misuse, as well as unauthorized access, alteration, disclosure or destruction of personal information. These measures include internal reviews of our data collection, storage and processing practices and security practices.  
4) ) iPerceptions restricts access to personal information to iPerceptions employees, contractors and agents who need to know that information in order to operate, develop or improve the Services. iPerceptions takes reasonable efforts to ensure all parties comply with confidentiality obligations.

10. CHANGES  
iPerceptions reserves the right to modify this Privacy Policy at any time, so please check for change notices on a regular basis. If iPerceptions decides to change its Privacy Policy in a material way, iPerceptions will notify You by means of a change notice on its Website so that You may access and review the changes to this document in advance of Your continued use of the Services or iPerceptions may, in its sole option, notify You by email of those changes before the change becoming effective. If You object to any changes, You may cancel, deactivate Your account, if any, or not respond to a survey. If You do not cancel, deactivate Your account, if any, or if You respond to a survey, and by continuing to use the Services after notice of change has published on a Website or has been sent to You, You will be considered as having expressly consented to the changed terms or practices.

11. OPTING OUT OF COMMUNICATIONS  
If you wish to subscribe to our newsletter(s) or other commercial electronic material, we will use your name and email address to send those communications to you. Except as expressly provided otherwise in this Privacy Policy, You and other Users have the right to opt out from receiving future communications in accordance with this Section, including for no longer receiving email invitations to take surveys which are sent by iPerceptions on behalf of Customers, You can contact us (see Contact Us Section 13.2), or follow the unsubscribe instructions included in each promotional email, if any, sent to You by selecting the opt-out link in the email.

12. LINKS TO OTHER WEBSITE  
The Website may contain links to other websites that are not owned or controlled by iPerceptions. Please be aware that iPerceptions cannot control the activities of third parties and iPerceptions doesn’t accept any responsibility for the privacy practices of such other websites and such third parties may not adhere to the same privacy policies. iPerceptions encourages You to be aware when You leave the Website and to read the privacy policies of each and every website that collects personally identifiable information.

13. LEGAL DISCLAIMER  
When requested by legal authorities to disclose personally identifiable information, iPerceptions will inform the court of various factors justifying confidentiality and respondent anonymity. However, iPerceptions may be required by law to disclose personally identifiable information where judicial or other governmental subpoenas, warrants, or orders are properly issued. Individuals’ unsubscribe option in no way limits iPerceptions’ use, disclosure or distribution of personally-identifiable information to the extent such use, disclosure or distribution is required by law, court order or other valid legal process. iPerceptions will communicate with the affected client as soon as possible, unless prohibited by law or court order. If iPerceptions completes a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or substantially all of its assets, you will be notified via a prominent notice on our website of any change in uses of your personal information, and choices you may have regarding your personal information. We may also disclose your personal information to any other third party with your prior consent.

14. GENERAL PROVISIONS

Notice to iPerceptions  
Any notice provided to iPerceptions pursuant to this Privacy Policy should be sent to iPerceptions, Inc. 3575 Boulevard St-Laurent Suite 310 Montreal, Quebec H2X 2T7, Canada, Attention: General Counsel.

Notice to You  
iPerceptions may, at its sole option, provide You with notices, including those regarding changes to this Privacy Policy, by email, regular mail, text message, postings on or within any of the Website.

15. CONTACT US  
If You have questions related to this Privacy Policy, please email us at: info@iPerceptions.com, write or send Your fax at: info@iPerceptions.com, write or send Your fax at::

iPerceptions Inc.  
3575 Boulevard St-Laurent  
Suite 310  
Montreal, Québec  
H2X 2T7  
Canada  
Fax: 514-484-2600

Attention: Chief Information Officer.

If you have questions or complaints regarding this Privacy Policy or practices, please contact iPerceptions (See Contact Us Section). If You are not satisfied with iPerceptions’ response You can contact TRUSTe.
